Katie Weagle

7 Lyndale Rd. Worcester, MA 01606 | 774-262-0018 | Katherine.Weagle@gmail.com | LinkedIn

Objective

I am an experienced writer with a strong background in technical communication, information design and development, release and project planning, editing, collaboration, and telecommuting. I believe that effective information design and user access are key to building a positive user experience for diverse audiences across multiple locales.

Experience

SENIOR TECHNICAL CONTENT DEVELOPER - RSA SECURITY | 2017 - PRESENT

- Writing, editing, and revising documentation and user interface content in multiple formats for a complex product.
- Leading a team of five writers responsible for delivering customer documentation for the entire RSA Archer Platform.
- Working in Agile with coworkers in diverse geo-locations.
- Tracking and writing for multiple diverse features per release on five scrum teams.
- Collaborating with the User Experience Design team to create a more user accessible interface.
- Maintaining close collaboration between cross-functional product teams, external globalization partners, and external localization vendors.
- Transforming the IDD globalization process through workflow changes and new software to benefit customers.
- Creating feature training and enablement videos using Camtasia.
- Presenting information about our documentation to customers at trainings and new hire orientations.

TECHNICAL CONTENT DEVELOPER - RSA SECURITY | 2012 - 2017

- Wrote, edited, and revised documentation for product development, support services, and end-user activities.
- Led the documentation projects for the Continuous Engineering team, including coordinating posting of localized deliverables.
- Presented information about our documentation to customers at product-specific trainings.
- Worked with multiple teams on diverse assignments and deliverables.
- Adhered to project schedules and contributed to the timely production of publications in multiple formats.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to create effective documentation.
- Utilized various authoring and desktop publishing software.
- Organized existing content into smaller information units for topic-based authoring.

ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL WRITER - ORACLE | 2011 - 2012

Contributed to the timely production and delivery of product documentation in multiple formats.

- Communicated with multiple product teams and departments.
- Tested, created, and reviewed new and existing documentation.
- Wrote and reviewed release notes, known issues, and updates to guides for multiple releases on various health science products.
- Organized new and existing graphics to improve accessibility.
- Aided in the development of product documentation standards.

WRITING TUTOR - UNIVERSITY OF MASSACHUSETTS - AMHERST | 2009 - 2011

- Helped students at undergrad and graduate level with writing.
- Attended regularly scheduled meetings and workshops.
- Managed the UMass Amherst Writing Center Facebook page.
- Trained in an intensive tutoring class and practicum.
- Conducted research on the image of the Writing Center through the use of SurveyMonkey and Facebook.
- Presented research on the image of the Writing Center at the Northeast Writing Center Association in Boston (April 2010).

MARKETING INTERN - COMMONWEALTH MEDICINE (UMASS MEDICAL) | 2010

- Updated inter- and intra-net sites using DreamWeaver and Ektron content editors.
- Conducted market research.
- Wrote project summaries.
- Composed briefing documents.

Education

B.A. ENGLISH - UNIVERSITY OF MASSACHUSETTS - AMHERST | 2011

Major: English

Certificates: Writing Tutor, Professional Writing and Technical Communication (PWTC)

Awards and Honors: W. Scott Jeffrey Award for PWTC, Departmental Honors in English, Commonwealth

Honors College, Graduated with Honors (cum laude)

Tools

Acrolinx, Adobe Acrobat, Adobe FrameMarker, Camtasia, Git, Jira, MadCap Analyzer, MadCap Capture, MadCap Flare, Microsoft Office Suit, Wiki